kaki narase sonzai wo
rock away your existence
koko ni iru to
shouting that you are here
arata na tabi ga ima hajimaru
a new journey begins now
kawari yuku kisetsu no naka wo ikinuku tabi ni bokura
as we survived through the changing seasons
chie to tsuyosa wo te ni ireta kedo JUST LOOKS LIKE SURVIVAL GAME
we gained knowledge and strength (just looks like a survival game)
nagareteku jikan no naka ni
but the forgotten memories
okizari ni shita omoi wo
of the feelings abandoned within the flows of time
wasureta koto sura wasurete ita
have also been lost
kuzure kaketa toki kodoku wo shitte
when sinking down we learned loneliness
deaeta bokura hitori ja nai
but now we've met each other we are no longer alone
sarake dase kanjou wo banjou no omoi wo
unveil your feelings those high emotions
namidame ga unmei wo kaete yuku
those tears will change your fate
yami ni uchi narase kodou wo
pound your heartbeat against the darkness
kitto aeru yo onaji itami no hata no moto de
we're sure to meet under the same flag of pain
Milady, the skies have begun
to look threatening.
We should seek lodging for the night
before we get rained on.
I see. Carry on.
Yes, milady.
What dense fog!
We cannot see what's up ahead.
What was that?
Is something the matter?
Lady Kayo!
Mystery
the
Cursed
Ghost
Castle
Of
I hear that it happened while the mistress
of the Land of Honey, Lady Kayo,
was on her way to visit the household
of her parents in Land of Candy.
Attendants from The Land of Candy
went out to meet them,
thinking it odd
that their arrival was delayed,
only to find that the palanquin and poles
had been cast away at the mountain pass.
I am told that Lady Kayo and all
of her attendants have disappeared.
Then, our task is to search
for the lady, right?
That is so.
Hinata's Byakugan
and Kiba and Akamaru's keen sense of smell
should prove helpful
in this search mission,
and Naruto is, well, just Naruto.
What are you saying, Grandma?
That I have nothing in particular
to recommend me?
But isn't that the case?
I think that you have good points, too,
Naruto.
Oh! Leave it to Hinata.
Go ahead and list them all
for Grandma Tsunade!
Come on, what are my good points?
Um... Let me see...
It shouldn't be that hard!
I didn't mean to make it seem that way.
Um... Well...
Hey, you two. Are you finished?
Say, Grandma,
there wouldn't be anything odd
happening in this mission, would there?
Something odd?
That is to say, might there perhaps...
be ghosts involved?
Ghosts? Are you afraid of such things?
Well, um... kind of.
There are no such things as ghosts.
Stop talking such nonsense
and get on your way.
Which brings us to the question
of where to, Fifth Hokage?
Kubisaki Pass.
Kubisaki Pass?
As in the Broken Neck Pass?
I knew I had a bad premonition.
Fool!
A Shinobi shouldn't dally
about such things. Get going!
You're scarier than any ghost!
We're off!
Excuse us.
It's always like this with that one.
Tsunade-sama,
Kubisaki Pass is where
the capital of the Land of Necks
once stood, isn't it?
The ruined castle of the Kubisaki Clan,
which met its destruction 50 years ago,
must still be there.
And what of it?
Ruined castles may be found
just about anywhere.
Have you caught
Naruto's cowardice bug, Shizune?
No, that's not it.
Oh, this is the spot.
The Broken Neck Pass.
It gives me the creeps, I tell you.
It's raining now. Let's hurry.
It's really coming down!
A castle.
I hadn't heard anything
about a castle standing here.
I have a bad feeling about this.
See, see?! This mission is starting
to get creepier and creepier.
But this may be a major clue.
Let's go.
Yeah. At this rate, we'll get soaking wet.
Hey, don't be in such a hurry!
What a magnificent castle.
Won't it be sort of rude
to suddenly intrude upon them?
It's almost night.
Maybe we'll be causing them trouble.
Naruto, don't tell me
you really are scared!
No way, I tell you!
Pull yourself together, Naruto.
Let's go.
The door opened by itself.
Excuse me, is anybody home?
The lights are turned on.
Please let us shelter here
from the rain for a bit!
Hey! Wait! Akamaru!
Excuse us.
Good evening.
Something sure smells good.
It's still warm.
Was someone here just a little while ago?
What's that?
That's one scary-looking guy.
I wonder if he's the master
of this castle.
If he's the master of this castle,
that makes him a feudal lord, right?
If this is the feudal lord's castle,
then the area around here
should be the capital.
But this is right on
the country borderline.
Hey! Akamaru!
What are you doing?
You shouldn't eat that
without permission.
— Naruto?
— What is it?
Don't startle me like that.
Just now, the painting's eyes moved!
You moron. How could a painting move?
You're such a scaredy cat.
The table's set for seven people.
So, what of it?
The Land of Honey party
that went missing also numbered seven.
The lady and her attendants
may still be in this castle.
Let's split up and search for them.
Wha...? Split up?
Since we're here together,
why don't we search together?
What do you say, Kiba? Hinata?
Naruto, stop talking like a kid.
This is a mission!
You don't have to scold me so much!
I know that!
Hey! Wait a minute!
I'm just not cut out
for this kind of stuff.
This is scarier than going to the bathroom
in the middle of the night.
This is creepy!
No!
Not again!
Kiba, Hinata, Akamaru!
I'm too scared to be alone!
Do you sense it, too? I'm sure
this is the scent of a human being.
It's here.
There's no one here.
I'll eat you up.
Who's that? Is someone there?
The ceiling...
Take that, you.
Look at all these books.
"The History of Neck Castle."
This was written 50 years ago!
"The enemy forces have already
surrounded the castle."
Our people were brutally slaughtered
and there are only a few of the soldiers
left in the castle.
It seems certain that I will not live
to see nightfall either.
But my thirst for vengeance
remains in the castle,
and I vow with this castle
to consume every last man,
every human that sets foot
within these walls...
"Signed, Gosa Kubisaki."
Consume?
I'll eat you.
What is this?
Gosa Kubisaki!
Crap!
Hinata! Hey!
Hinata! Pull yourself together!
Naruto.
Naruto, Hinata, are you all right?
Kiba, Akamaru!
A castle that fell 50 years ago?
What nonsense.
That is how the scroll is dated.
It says that anyone who enters
this castle will be eaten alive.
True, we have been swallowed whole.
— Naruto!
— Are you okay? Hey!
That hurt.
There he is!
— I'm sorry.
— What is this?
This isn't the armor of the Kubisaki Clan.
I wonder if this belonged
to an enemy soldier.
There's more over there.
They are different armors.
Those armors bear the crest
of the Kubisaki Clan.
Let's hurry up and get out of here!
That's the same armor as in the painting.
Could it be...
that this is the real Gosa Kubisaki?
Gosa Kubisaki?
What's going on?
He's melting!
What is this?
Something smells really sour.
There is something strange
about this castle.
— Hinata!
— Yeah.
Byakugan!
The whole wall is covered
with a flow of Chakra.
Why?
It's moving!
This wall seems to be alive!
What if...?
Gentle Fist!
Are you all right, Hinata?
Uh-huh.
I've seen something very similar to this
somewhere before.
The giant toad summoned
by the Pervy Sage...
from inside its stomach!
Inside its stomach?!
Then, I wonder if, by chance,
this smell could be... gastric juices?!
Gosa Kubisaki invoked
the Summoning Jutsu
before the fall of the castle.
But the thing he summoned...
was big enough to swallow
the entire castle whole.
From the time we entered the castle,
we, too, have been gobbled up!
But why would this thing go to the trouble
of transforming to a castle to eat us?
I don't know.
What was that?
Help!
Are you the lady of the Land of Honey?
She's embedded in the wall.
We are from the Village Hidden
in the Leaves.
We have come to help you.
Here, I'll help you out now.
— It's no use.
— Please hang on!
Oh, no! This thing is rounding up
all the humans inside here
and returning to its original form.
At this rate, we're in danger, too!
Naruto, Hinata,
we've got to get out of here!
Man Beast Clone!
Fang over Fang!
I am the castle.
And by order of my master, Gosa,
I am to eat all who set foot within.
— Naruto!
— Ouch.
I'll eat you.
How can we get out of its stomach?!
I don't know.
If this creature was summoned,
then there should be a scroll
for the contract.
If we tear that up, then this creature
should return to the world it came from.
Is that so?
— Hinata!
— Right!
Byakugan!
Found it.
It's up above,
probably in the castle tower.
How are we supposed
to get up there like this?!
The wall's Chakra have begun
to stabilize again.
Who's that?
Gosa Kubisaki!
I won't be fooled again.
That, too, is just a phantom
created by the Summoning.
Wait! He looks different
from the one before.
What's he doing?
He seems to want us to follow him.
Huh? He disappeared!
Naruto, over there.
Oh, it's the scroll!
It's starting to act up again.
— Hurry, Naruto!
— Right!
This is...
It's the true form
of the summoned animal.
The concentration of acid is increasing.
Hey, let's hurry and wind things up!
Wait a minute.
What if, when this summoned animal
goes back to where it came from,
it takes us with it, too?
We'll just have to take our chances.
We gotta do this!
Right.
Did that do it?
What the...?!
— Naruto!
Over there, Naruto.
It should be possible
to tear the wall at that spot.
Okay! Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Rasengan!
Naruto!
The lord of this castle must have died
resenting the people
who seized the castle from him.
But he also led us
to where the scroll was hidden.
So, does that mean that he decided
to let go of his grudge?
Surely that must be the case.
What's more, he must have felt sorry
for the summoned animal
that served him nobly for 50 years
and wanted to release it.
I see.
Then maybe he was waiting
for someone
to release the summoned animal
from its spell.
And now, it has finally returned
to its own world.
hoshikuzu suchasucha sucha odoru
on a checkerboard night
ichimatsu no yoru ni
when the stardust's are rapidly dancing
aa mada kaeri takunai to kuchi ni wa dasenai naa
I just can't come out and say, "ah, I don't want to go home yet"
omowa seburi terii
suggestively
aisubeki kao ni tsuba wo misutaa kuriketto
spat at that beloved face, mister cricket
asekusai suteeji no ue de hikaru toronboon no
the trombone gradually going off-key
picchi ga dandan hazureteitteiru no mo kininaru kedo
while on the sweaty center stage does bug me
sonna koto yori kono nai mune no moyamoya wa sakki
but more importantly, the fuzziness I feel in my undeveloped chest,
nonda koora no sei kashira nee
I wonder If it's from that coke I just drank?
How did it go, Bushy Brow?
Hush. He doesn't look himself.
He sure looks gloomy.
The results were bad.
I'd say considerably.
Huh? "Considerably"?
It can't be helped.
It must have been considerable.
Then... could it be that Bushy Brow is...'?
Yes... I'm sorry but...
Then he's considerably...
considerably. . . '?!
Next time:
"The Third Super Beast. The Greatest Rival."